<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on BTech CSE 5th sem syllabus</title>
    <link>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on BTech CSE 5th sem syllabus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 14:41:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/pec-it501b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 14:41:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/pec-it501b/</guid>
      <description>~/ ~/posts/
Introduction Overview of Artificial intelligence- Problems of AI, AI technique, Tic - Tac - Toe problem. Intelligent Agents Agents &amp;amp; environment, nature of environment, structure of agents, goal based agents, utility based agents, learning agents. Problem Solving Problems, Problem Space &amp;amp; search: Defining the problem as state space search, production system, problem characteristics, issues in the design of search program
Search techniques Solving problems by searching :problem solving agents, searching for solutions; uniform search strategies: breadth first search, depth first search, depth limited search, bidirectional search, comparing uniform search strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Industrial Management</title>
      <link>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/hsmc501/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 14:40:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/hsmc501/</guid>
      <description>~/ ~/posts/
Introduction System- concept, definition, types, parameters, variables and behavior. Management – definition and functions. Organization structure: i. Definition. ii. Goals. iii. Factors considered in formulating structure. iv. Types. v. Advantages and disadvantages. vi. Applications. Concept, meaning and importance of division of labor, scalar &amp;amp; functional processes, span of control, delegation of authority, centralization and decentralization in industrial management. Organizational culture and climate – meaning, differences and factors affecting them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Oriented Programming</title>
      <link>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/pcc-cs503/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 14:38:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/pcc-cs503/</guid>
      <description>~/ ~/posts/
Abstract data types and their specification. How to implement an ADT. Concrete state space, concrete invariant, abstraction function. Implementing operations, illustrated by the Text example.
Features of object-oriented programming. Encapsulation, object identity, polymorphism – but not inheritance.
Inheritance in OO design. Design patterns. Introduction and classification. The iterator pattern.
Model-view-controller pattern. Commands as methods and as objects. Implementing OO language features. Memory management.
Generic types and collections GUIs. Graphical programming with Scale and Swing .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating Systems</title>
      <link>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/pcc-cs502/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 14:37:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/pcc-cs502/</guid>
      <description>~/ ~/posts/
Objective To learn the mechanisms of OS to handle processes and threads and their communication
To learn the mechanisms involved in memory management in contemporary OS
To gain knowledge on distributed operating system concepts that includes architecture, Mutual exclusion algorithms, deadlock detection algorithms and agreement protocols
To know the components and management aspects of concurrency management
Pre-Requisite Computer Organization &amp;amp;Architecture Introduction: Generations of Operating systems, Concept of Operating Systems, Types of Operating Systems, OS Services, System Calls, Structure of an OS - Layered, Monolithic, Microkernel Operating Systems, Concept of Virtual Machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiler Design</title>
      <link>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/pcc-cs501/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 14:36:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/pcc-cs501/</guid>
      <description>~/ ~/posts/
Objective To understand and list the different stages in the process of compilation.
Identify different methods of lexical analysis
Design top-down and bottom-up parsers
Identify synthesized and inherited attributes
Develop syntax directed translation schemes
Develop algorithms to generate code for a target machine
Introduction to Compiling Compilers, Analysis of the source program, The phases of the compiler, Cousins of the compiler.
Lexical Analysis The role of the lexical analyzer, Tokens, Patterns, Lexemes, Input buffering, Specifications of a token, Recognition of a tokens, Finite automata, From a regular expression to an NFA, From a regular expression to NFA, From a regular expression to DFA, Design of a lexical analyzer generator (Lex)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/esc501/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 14:31:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btech-cse-5th-sem-syllabus.netlify.app/posts/esc501/</guid>
      <description>~/ ~/posts/
Overview of System Analysis &amp;amp; Design , Business System Concept, System Development Life Cycle, Waterfall Model , Spiral Model, Feasibility Analysis, Technical Feasibility, Cost- Benefit Analysis, COCOMO model.
System Design – Context diagram and DFD, Problem Partitioning, Top-Down And Bottom-Up design; Decision tree, decision table and structured English; Functional vs. Object- Oriented approach.
Coding &amp;amp; Documentation – Structured Programming, OO Programming, Information Hiding, Reuse, System Documentation.
Testing – Levels of Testing, Integration Testing, Test case Specification, Reliability Assessment, Validation &amp;amp; Verification Metrics, Monitoring &amp;amp; Control.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
